A Guide to the Records the Virginia Commission on Youth, 1991-2001
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Commission on Youth, 1991-2001
The Library of Virginia
42945
34.35 cubic feet (35 Boxes)
Virginia Commission on Youth
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 42945 was transferred from the Virginia Commission on Youth on November 6, 2006.
Historical Information
The Virginia Commission on Youth was established by the 1989 General Assembly (statutes §30-174 and §30-175). The formation of the Commission was a legislative response to a two-year study examining the issues related to services to chronic status offenders. Virginia code mandates the Commission "to study and provide recommendations addressing the needs of and services to the Commonwealth's youth and families." Enacted in 1989, the Commission began operations in 1991.
The Commission on Youth is a standing legislative commission of the Virginia General Assembly. It is comprised of twelve members: six Delegates appointed by the Speaker of the House, three Senators appointed by the Senate Committee on Rules, and three citizens appointed by the Governor.
The Commission on Youth provides a legislative forum in which complex issues related to Virginia youth and their families may be explored and resolved. The Commission provides a bipartisan forum for complex issues related to youth and their families. It is responsible for monitoring developments in federal, state and local policies and laws which impact youth and their families, while also contributing to the General Assembly's ability to make sound policy decisions based on well-studied and reasoned recommendations. The Commission assists General Assembly members in developing bills on study issues which reflect consensus among key agencies, organizations and special interests. The Commission also conducts legislative studies on issues related to youth and their families, and serves as a resource for constituent concerns and the general public. Members of the Commission often speak to professional associations, civic and community groups about the legislative process, state and national policy issues impacting youth, and specific topical areas, as well as educate interested groups on Commission studies. Members may also serve on varied private and governmental task forces convened on children's issues.
Each year the Virginia Commission on Youth compiles a summary of legislative action impacting youth and their families across the Commonwealth. The Commission also produces a yearly newsletter, the General Assembly Overview, which outlines the year's legislative and gubernatorial actions affecting children and their families.
Scope and Content
Accession 42945: Study documentation records, 1991-2001, include records related juvenile detention, juvenile justice reform, truants and runaways, juvenile records, Virginia Juvenile Community Crime Control Act, serious juvenile offenders, education needs of homeless youth, youth suicide prevention, early intervention services, incarcerated youth, guardians ad litem, and adoption laws. These records may contain correspondence, articles, briefing materials, legislation, policies, presentation, reports, statistics, summaries, and surveys. Records have been minimally processed and are in original order.
Note: The Commission on Youth studies respond to issues identified by the Virginia General Assembly. During the 1990s there were a number of juvenile justice issues related to the newly established Virginia Juvenile Community Crime Control Act (VJCCCA). Studies during this time period were in sequential order and/or interrelated, in that issues raised in one year were also investigated in subsequent years, directly or indirectly. In these files, research gathered in one study might have been used in another study, thus these files are not always clearly distinguishable and may be intermingled.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Study documentation records, 1991-2001 (42945)
Contents List
- Study documentation records, 1991-2001., Extent: 35 boxes. (Box 1-35)
  - Student Discipline, Secure Detention, Post-Dispositional Detention, Juvenile Justice Reform, 1991-2001.
    - Governor's Commission on Juvenile Justice Reform - Recommendations and background report of the Courts and Sentencing Subcommittee, undated. (Box 1)
    - Commonwealth's Attorney - Surveys on juvenile detention, 1994. (Box 1)
    - Court Service Unit Directors - Surveys on juvenile detenion, 1994. (Box 1)
    - Detenion Home Superintendents - Surveys on juvenile detention, 1994. (Box 1)
    - Identification of Community Alternative Programs - Dept. of Youth and Family Services (DYFS) Commission Project, 1994. (Box 1)
    - Juvenile Justice System Overview (HJR 260), 1993. (Box 1)
    - Briefing materials - SPSS Analysis and survey comments, 1995. (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (HJR 446), 1992-1993. (Box 1a)
    - Juvenile Justice - Other states, 1994-1995. (Box 1a)
    - Juvenile Justice - Speeches (HJR 604), 1993-1999. (Box 1a)
    - Superintendents - Judges Liaison Committee meeting, 1995 Nov 6. (Box 1a)
    - Senate Finance Committee presentation, 1995 Aug 31. (Box 1a)
    - Orientation materials, 1992-1993. (Box 1a)
    - Student discipline statutes (HJR 186), undated. (Box 1a)
    - Disciplinary case summary (HJR 242), undated. (Box 1a)
    - HJR 604, undated. (Box 1a)
    - Young Offenders - Overview, undated. (Box 1a)
    - Lt. Governor Beyer, 1994. (Box 1a)
  - Juvenile Justice Reform, 1991-2001.
    - DYFS - State ward per diems / Detention home rates (FY1994), 1994. (Box 2a)
    - DYFS - Funding information, 1994. (Box 2a)
    - Databook - Secure detention, 1996. (Box 2a)
    - Databook - Juvenile arrests, 1996. (Box 2a)
    - Databook - JCC admissions, 1996. (Box 2a)
    - Survey results, 1995. (Box 2a)
    - Intake complaints by locality, 1993. (Box 2a)
    - Governor's Commission on Juvenile Justice Reform - Reports, 1995. (Box 2a)
    - Commonwealth Poll - Public opinion regarding the Juvenile Justice System in Virginia, 1995. (Box 2a)
    - Virginia Uniform Crime Statistics, 1994. (Box 2a)
    - Survey presentation data, 1995. (Box 2a)
    - Briefing packages / presentations, 1995. (Box 2a)
    - Sheriff detention travel costs, 1994. (Box 2a)
    - Detention home data, 1993. (Box 2a)
    - DYFS - Violations charges in detention, 1994. (Box 2a)
    - Senator Houck's presentation / data on budget, 1995. (Box 2a)
    - DYFS - Serious offender status, 1995. (Box 2a)
    - DYFS - Data funding committments, 1992-1993. (Box 2a)
    - Travel and utilization of a non-participating jurisdiction, 1993. (Box 2a)
    - Transfer / convictions, 1995. (Box 2a)
    - Juvenile Justice Program Alternatives, undated. (Box 2a)
    - Juvenile Justice policy statements, 1994. (Box 2a)
    - Juvenile Justice reform bill, 1996. (Box 2a)
    - Fifteen Point Proposal, undated. (Box 2a)
    - Task Force (HJR 604), 1995. (Box 2a)
    - Survey correspondence (HJR 604), 1995. (Box 2a)
    - Survey results (HJR 604), 1995. (Box 2a)
    - Juvenile justice articles, 1993. (Box 2a)
    - Public opinion poll (HJR 604), 1995. (Box 2a)
    - Presentations to Senate Finance Committee, 1991-1995. (Box 2a)
    - Surveys of other states, 1992-1993. (Box 2a)
    - American Corrections Association - Directory, 1991. (Box 2a)
    - Profile of Delinquency Cases at Various Stages of the Florida Juvenile Justice System, 1992. (Box 2a)
    - DYFS - Complete listing of offense codes, 1991. (Box 2a)
    - Circuit Court Judges - Survey of juvenile justice, 1995. (Box 2b)
    - Elementary School Principals - Survey on juvenile justice, 1995. (Box 2b)
    - Middle School Principals - Survey on juvenile justice, 1995. (Box 2b)
    - Family Assessment and Planning Teams - Survey on juvenile justice, 1995. (Box 2b)
    - Survey recipients, 1994-1995. (Box 2b)
    - Secure detention, 1999. (Box 2c)
    - Secure detention - Staffing, undated. (Box 2c)
    - Post-Dispositional Programs, 1999. (Box 2c)
    - Fiscal information (FY99), 1999. (Box 2c)
    - Construction, 1999. (Box 2c)
    - Detention home capacity, 1999. (Box 2c)
    - Money issues (DJJ), 1999. (Box 2c)
    - Detention home data sheets, 1999. (Box 2c)
    - Presentations, 1993-1994. (Box 2c)
    - Secure Juvenile Detention Study (HJR 260) - Meeting, 1994. (Box 2c)
    - Study on Juvenile Justice Reform (HJR 604) - Meetings, 1995. (Box 2c)
    - Detention statistics, 1993. (Box 2c)
    - Articles - Recommendations on juvenile detention, 1989-1991. (Box 2c)
    - Articles - Overcrowding, undated. (Box 2c)
    - Youth Law Center (HJR 260), 1992. (Box 2c)
    - Study of predispositional detention in juvenile detention homes (HJR 587), 1999. (Box 2c)
    - Detention Home Study Task Force (HJR 446), 1993. (Box 2c)
    - Surveys (HJR 260), 1994. (Box 2c)
    - Historic detention funding, 1991-1998. (Box 2c)
    - Juvenile correctional centers, 1994-1999. (Box 2c)
    - Research methodology (HJR 260), 1994. (Box 2c)
    - Learning Center data, 1992. (Box 2c)
    - Secure detention commitments (FY88, FY89), 1990. (Box 2c)
    - Detention data, 1987-1991. (Box 2c)
    - Intake data (FY93), 1993. (Box 2c)
    - Initial Survey Results presentation (HJR 260), 1994. (Box 2c)
    - Presentation (DJJ), 1999. (Box 2c)
    - Casey Foundation - Working drafts, undated. (Box 2c)
    - Press (HJR 260), 1992-1994. (Box 2c)
    - Risk assessment (HJR 260), 1994. (Box 2c)
    - Conditions of confinement (HJR 260), 1993. (Box 2c)
    - Local detention master plans, 1986, 1992. (Box 2c)
    - Other states - Criteria, undated. (Box 2c)
    - Articles - Detention, 1991-1993. (Box 2c)
    - Non-secure detention, 1991-1992. (Box 2c)
    - Detention Study Methodology (HJR 260), 1994. (Box 2c)
    - Definitions / Code, undated. (Box 2c)
    - Secure detention - Maps, undated. (Box 2c)
    - Detention risk assessments, 1994, 1999. (Box 2c)
    - Survey code books (HJR 260), 1994. (Box 2c)
    - Juvenile Justice Task Force (HJR 604) - Meeting, 1995 Oct 13. (Box 2d)
    - Juvenile Justice Task Force (HJR 604) - Meeting, 1995 Nov 21. (Box 2d)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1995. (Box 2d)
    - Juvenile Justice correspondence, 1992-1993. (Box 2d)
    - Legislation - Other states, 1991-1993. (Box 2d)
    - Juvenile Justice profile, 1991-1993. (Box 2d)
    - Recidivism, 1991. (Box 2d)
    - Standards of supervision, undated. (Box 2d)
    - Treatment modalities, undated. (Box 2d)
    - Service systems, undated. (Box 2d)
    - Program models, undated. (Box 2d)
    - Delay reduction (HJR 604), 1995. (Box 2d)
    - Presentations (HJR 604), 1995. (Box 2d)
    - Study Plan (HJR 604), 1995. (Box 2d)
    - Waiver, undated. (Box 2d)
    - Study of Serious Offenders (HJR 43), 1993. (Box 2d)
    - Study Plan (HJR 43), 1993. (Box 2d)
    - Juvenile transfer process, 1995. (Box 2d)
    - Bibliography, undated. (Box 2d)
    - National data transfer, undated. (Box 2d)
    - Articles, 1992-1993. (Box 2d)
    - Serious Juvenile Offenders - Task Force meetings, 1993 May-Nov. (Box 2d)
    - Legislation - HB 1243 and SB 528, 1994. (Box 2d)
    - Juvenile Justice Public Hearing, 1993 Nov 16. (Box 2d)
    - JLARC staff briefings, 1995-1996. (Box 2d)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-1996. (Box 2d)
    - Risk assessment instrument ofr juvenile felony offenders (HJR 70), 1996. (Box 2d)
    - Juvenile Justice Reform - Staffing cost (HJR 604), 1996. (Box 2d)
    - Juvenile Justice compromis bill (HB 251), 1996. (Box 2d)
    - Alternative draft - Cost proposals, 1996. (Box 2d)
    - Cost calculations, 1996. (Box 2d)
    - Subcommittee presentations - House Appropriations, 1996 Feb. (Box 2d)
    - Juvenile Justice System Task Force - Meetings, 1995. (Box 2d)
    - Surveys on Juvenile Detention - Juvenile and Domestic Relations District Court Judges, 1995. (Box 2e)
    - Surveys on Juvenile Detention - Sheriffs and Chiefs of Police, 1995. (Box 2e)
    - Surveys on Juvenile Detention - Commonwealth's Attorneys, 1995. (Box 2e)
    - Articles on juvenile justice, 1990-1993. (Box 2f)
    - Articles on boot camps, undated. (Box 2f)
    - Model programs, 1993. (Box 2f)
    - JJDP statistics, 1992. (Box 2f)
    - Other states - Wisconsin, 1992. (Box 2f)
    - Community Service, 1996. (Box 2f)
    - Overview of the Juvenile Justice System, 1997-1999. (Box 2f)
    - Commitment profiles (DJJ), 2000. (Box 2f)
    - Virginia Coalition for Juvenile Justice, undated. (Box 2f)
    - Secure facilities (HB 711), 1998. (Box 2f)
    - Surveys on Juvenile Detention - Court Service Unit Directors, 1995. (Box 2f)
    - Surveys on Juvenile Detention - Court Appointed Counsel, 1995. (Box 2f)
    - Surveys on Juvenile Detention - School Principals, 1995. (Box 2f)
    - Surveys on Juvenile Detention - Chiefs of Police, 1995. (Box 2f)
    - Surveys on Juvenile Detention - Public Defenders, 1995. (Box 2f)
    - Budget amendments (SJR 440), 2002. (Box 2f)
    - Tracking Work Group (HJR 604), 1995. (Box 2g)
    - Tracking and code book, 1995. (Box 2g)
    - Survey research and methodology, 1995. (Box 2g)
    - Surveys on Juvenile Detention - Juvenile and Domestic Relations District Court Judges, 1994. (Box 2g)
    - Surveys on Juvenile Detention - School Principals, 1995. (Box 2g)
    - Surveys on Juvenile Detention - School Principals, 1995. (Box 2h)
    - Presentation data print outs (HJR 260), undated. (Box 2h)
    - Statewide aggregate data, 1995. (Box 2h)
    - Child Care Days data, 1994. (Box 2h)
    - Guidelines Determining the Length of Stay of Juveniles Indeterminately Committed to DJJ, 1998. (Box 2h)
    - Detention Task Force Report (DYFS), 1992 Aug. (Box 2h)
    - Miscellaneous data printouts, 1995. (Box 2h)
  - Truants and Runaways, 1997-1999.
    - Workgroups - HJR 93, Study of Truants and Runaways (Status of Offenders, Children in Need of Services and Children in Need of Supervision), 1998. (Box 3a)
    - Workgroups - HJR 490, 1997-1998. (Box 3a)
    - Federal issues, undated. (Box 3a)
    - Glossary of Child Service Related Terms (HJR 490), undated. (Box 3a)
    - Scenarios, 199l7. (Box 3a)
    - Assessment Centers, 1997. (Box 3a)
    - Runaway services, 1997. (Box 3a)
    - National laws, undated. (Box 3a)
    - Transparencies (HJR 93), 1998. (Box 3a)
    - National truancy models, undated. (Box 3a)
    - Task Force on Truants and Runaways - Meeting, 1997 July 22. (Box 3a)
    - Task Force on Truants and Runaways - Meeting, 1997 Sept 17. (Box 3a)
    - Task Force on Truants and Runaways - Meeting, 1997 Nov 13. (Box 3a)
    - Media clippings, 1997. (Box 3a)
    - Interim report and presentation, 1998. (Box 3a)
    - Workgroups, 1998. (Box 3a)
    - RHYA grantees, 1997. (Box 3a)
    - Virginia shelters - Budgets and evaluation, 199l7-1998. (Box 3a)
    - Task Force on Truants and Runaways - Meeting, 1998 July- 29. (Box 3a)
    - Task Force on Truants and Runaways - Meeting, 1998 Sept 25. (Box 3a)
    - Task Force on Truants and Runaways - Meeting, 1998 Oct 30. (Box 3a)
    - Task Force on Truants and Runaways - Meeting, 1998 Nov 23. (Box 3a)
    - Truancy laws, undated. (Box 3a)
    - Local truancy models, 1997. (Box 3a)
    - GED Prep / Test costs, 1998-1999. (Box 3a)
    - Survey - HJR 93, 1998. (Box 3b)
    - Task Force on Truants and Runaways - Meeting, 1998 Sept 25. (Box 3b)
    - Task Force on Truants and Runaways - Sanctions Work Group meeting, 1998 Nov 10. (Box 3b)
    - Study of Truans and Runaways (HD 64), 1998. (Box 3b)
    - Runaway and Homeless Youth (RHYA) - Description and overview, 1998. (Box 3b)
    - Resources / articles, 1998. (Box 3b)
    - Laws - Other states, 1998. (Box 3b)
    - GED Survey - Other states, 1998. (Box 3b)
    - Second Year activities, 1998-1999. (Box 3b)
    - GED surveys / programs, 1998-1999. (Box 3b)
    - Surveys, 1998. (Box 10a)
  - Juvenile Records, 2002.
    - Juvenile Records and Information Sharing - An Overview of Federal and State Law, Practice and Procedure in Virginia, 2002. (Box 3b)
    - Juvenile records legislation, 2002. (Box 3b)
    - Research materials, 2002. (Box 3b)
    - Study of Juvenile Records - Advisory Group meetings, 2002. (Box 3b)
    - Study of Confidentiality of Juvenile Records (HD 54), 1994. (Box 3c)
    - Trainer packet, undated. (Box 3c)
    - Study of Juvenile Records - Work Group meeting, 2002 June 25. (Box 3c)
    - Study of Juvenile Records - Work Group meeting, 2002 Sept 9. (Box 3c)
    - Study of Juvenile Records - Work Group meeting, 2002 Oct 9. (Box 3c)
    - Recommendations, 2002. (Box 3c)
    - Legislation and regulations, 2002. (Box 3c)
    - Legislation and regulations - FOIA, 2002. (Box 3c)
    - Legislation and regulations - FERPA, 2002. (Box 3c)
    - Decision Matrix for 2003 General Assembly, 2002 Nov 19. (Box 3c)
    - Presentation to the Superintendents-Judges Liaison Committee, 2002 Oct 31. (Box 3c)
  - Virginia Juvenile Community Crime Control Act (VJCCCA) / Serious Offenders [intermingled], 1992-2001.
    - Juvenile Justice Reform, 1995-1996. (Box 4a)
    - Evaluation of the VJCCCA - Preliminary Report of the Virginia Commission on Youth, 1998. (Box 4a)
    - First Annual Report of the VJCCCA, 2001 Jan. (Box 4a)
    - Secure detention, 1994-1995. (Box 4a)
    - Presentations, 1997. (Box 4a)
    - Plan contacts, 1997. (Box 4a)
    - Ad Hoc Work Groups, 1997-1998. (Box 4a)
    - Surveys - Judges, 1997. (Box 4a)
    - Comprehensive Services Act, 1997. (Box 4a)
    - Telephone survey, 1997. (Box 4a)
    - Child Care Days, 1997. (Box 4a)
    - Crime Control meeting, 1997 June 24. (Box 4a)
    - Board on Juvenile Justice - VJCCCA Plan, 1998. (Box 4a)
    - Funding, 1997-1998. (Box 4a)
    - Surveys - VJCCCA Coordinators, 1997. (Box 4a)
    - Former grant programs, 1995. (Box 4a)
    - Community Programs budget and expenditure reports, 1995. (Box 4a)
    - Spreadsheets, 1997. (Box 4a)
    - Funding information by locality, 1996. (Box 4a)
    - Telephone survey (P-Y), 1997. (Box 4b)
    - Survey - Offices of Youth, 1999. (Box 4b)
    - Correspondence - 2nd Year, 1999. (Box 4b)
    - Program Matrix, 1999. (Box 4b)
    - Office of Youth - Regional meeting, 1999. (Box 4b)
    - Offices of Youth (DJJ) - Standards, undated. (Box 4b)
    - Correspondence, 1997. (Box 4b)
    - Legislation, 1999. (Box 4b)
    - Survey, 1999. (Box 4b)
    - Role of Offices on Youth Study, 1999-2000. (Box 4b)
    - Reports and presentations, 1998-2000. (Box 4b)
    - Surveys (A-H), 1997. (Box 5c)
    - Budget, 1996-1997. (Box 5a)
    - Hold harmless - 2nd run local appropriations, 1994. (Box 5a)
    - Formula information given to DYFS, 1995. (Box 5a)
    - Residential care admissions data by locality (DYFS), 1993. (Box 5a)
    - Appropriations, 1997. (Box 5a)
    - Training material (DJJ), 1997. (Box 5a)
    - Funding sheets, 1997. (Box 5a)
    - Team notes, 1997. (Box 5a)
    - Maintenance effort, 1998. (Box 5a)
    - Local MOE calculations, 1998. (Box 5a)
    - Financial presentation (HJR 160), 1994-1996. (Box 5a)
    - Funding, 1996. (Box 5a)
    - Detention / Alternative Block Grant Program capacity needs and usage information, 1997. (Box 5a)
    - Residential Care, 1990-1997. (Box 5a)
    - Budget bill reconciliation (HJR 260), 1994-1996. (Box 5a)
    - Funding formula (HJR 260), 1995. (Box 5a)
    - Other states (research), undated. (Box 5b)
    - Post dispositional options, undated. (Box 5b)
    - Information / Studies, undated. (Box 5b)
    - Statutes, undated. (Box 5b)
    - Transfer statutes, undated. (Box 5b)
    - Surveys needing follow up, undated. (Box 5b)
    - Dispositional programs descriptions, undated. (Box 5b)
    - Surveys on juvenile transfers, 1993. (Box 5b)
    - Study of Serious Juvenile Offenders - Reports, 1992. (Box 5d)
    - Serious offender legislation - Financial analysis and information, 1993-1994. (Box 5d)
    - CHINS presentation, 1987. (Box 5d)
    - Status offender code, undated. (Box 5d)
    - Status offenses, undated. (Box 5d)
    - Study of Serious Juvenile Offenders - Report, 1993. (Box 5d)
    - Dispositional options, undated. (Box 5d)
    - Transfer statutes - Other states, undated. (Box 5d)
    - National transfer statutes review, 1993. (Box 5d)
    - Public hearing, 1993. (Box 5d)
    - Virginia survey results, 1993. (Box 5d)
    - Transfer data, 1988-1995. (Box 5d)
    - Survey presentation data, 1994. (Box 5d)
    - Block grant cuts, 1995. (Box 5d)
    - Reports on juvenile arrests, 1998. (Box 5d)
    - District Court judges surveys, 1993. (Box 5d)
    - Surveys on juvenile transfers - Other states, 1992. (Box 5d)
  - Education Needs of Homeless Youth, 1996-1997.
    - Work group meetings (HJR 181), 1996. (Box 6)
    - Previous homeless studies, 1992. (Box 6)
    - Service needs / articles, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - State models on interagency planning, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Rent reduction tax credit, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Virginia homeless children data, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - VACH day care survey, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Virginia child care for the homeless, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Methodology (HJR 524), 1997. (Box 6)
    - McKinney Act, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Work group meetings, 1997. (Box 6)
    - School programs, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Homeless shelters contacts, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Cumulative homeless funding in Virginia, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Hearing testimony, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Virginia homeless statistics, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Study document (HJR 181), 1996. (Box 6)
    - Homeless medical coverage, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Characteristics of homeless women and children, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (HJR 181), 1996. (Box 6)
    - National funding summaries, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Domestic violence / Homelessness, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Homeless overview, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - National organizations, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Foster care, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Homeless data, 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Study of the Needs of Homeless Children - Reports, 1997; 1998. (Box 6)
  - Youth Suicide Prevention, 1988-2002.
    - Correspondence and reports, 1988-2001. (Box 7)
    - Annual Report on the Virginia Youth Suicide Prevention Plan (HD 22), 2002. (Box 7)
    - Study of Suicide in the Commonwealth (SD 16), 2000. (Box 7)
    - Youth Suicide Prevention Plan (HD 29), 2001. (Box 7)
    - Publications - Other states, 1988-2002. (Box 7)
    - Articles, publications and presentations, 1998-2001. (Box 7)
  - Early Intervention Services, 1992-1995.
    - Early Intervention Task Force, 1994-1995. (Box 8)
    - Early Intervention Task Force - Meetings, 1995. (Box 8)
    - Early Intervention Task Force - Public Hearing, 1994. (Box 8)
    - Study of Prevention and Early Intervention, 1992. (Box 8)
  - Youth Assets Pilot Program, 2000-2003.
    - Childhood obesity, 2003. (Box 8)
    - Female juvenile offenders, 2002. (Box 8)
    - Pilot Program, 2001. (Box 8)
    - Data, 2001. (Box 8)
    - Correspondence and meetings, 2001. (Box 8)
    - Fluvanna County, 2000-2001. (Box 8)
    - Healthy communities, 2000. (Box 8)
    - Application, 2000. (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 2000-2002. (Box 8)
    - Budget, 2001. (Box 8)
    - Hampton Coalition for Youth, 2001. (Box 8)
    - Urban League of Hampton Roads, 2001. (Box 8)
    - Tazewell County, 2000-2001. (Box 8)
  - Needs of Incarcerated Children, 1992-1994.
    - Needs of Children Who Are Incarcerated, 1994. (Box 9)
    - Articles, 1992-1994. (Box 9)
    - Bibliography, 1992-1994. (Box 9)
    - Reports, 1993-1994. (Box 9)
  - Role of Guardian Ad Litem (GAL) and Courtroom Environment in Child Sexual Assault Cases, 1989-1997.
    - Meeting summaries, 1993-1994. (Box 9)
    - Charts, undated. (Box 9)
    - Alternate indigent defense systems, 1989. (Box 9)
    - GAL training proposals, 1993. (Box 9)
    - GAL standards of practice, 1993. (Box 9)